<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Boa Blog</title><link href="http://blog.boa.nu/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.boa.nu/feeds/tag-blog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.boa.nu/</id><updated>2012-10-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Another blog is born</title><link href="http://blog.boa.nu/2012/10/another-blog-is-born.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Lars Solberg</name></author><id>tag:blog.boa.nu,2012-10-21:2012/10/another-blog-is-born.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I am starting a new blog in late 2012, I feel like I am a little too late. But there is several reasons I haven't started blogging before now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't think anyone really cares about my day to day stuff, so why write about it..?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think it is more exiting to work on my own projects than writing about them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't want to use a lot of time writing something when I lock my writing down deep inside a database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've always felt like it is too late to start writing a blog. No kidding, I have had that feeling since 2003.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the reason I will try to write a couple of blog articles from time to time now is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; project on my todo list have been inactive for too long now. I want those todo's out of my head :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want a personal place I can lookup my own projects. I really want a good place to document problems. Because of that, this blog will be more of an polished notebook for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think it is time to learn myself more &lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/"&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt; Hell, everyone should learn some markdown! And/or &lt;a href="http://fletcherpenney.net/multimarkdown/"&gt;multimarkdown&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two things usually makes me happy when I try to figure out a problem using Google. And that is finding a &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/"&gt;stackoverflow&lt;/a&gt; post, or a blog post. As I already am &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/users/452081/xeor"&gt;contributing to stackoverflow&lt;/a&gt;, I figured out a blog will also be nice to have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the stuff I am going to write about will be in the very geeky genre. All the geeky goodness will be in the &lt;em&gt;geeky&lt;/em&gt; category. There will also be a &lt;em&gt;priv&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;misc&lt;/em&gt; category. But not many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All tags and categories will have its own ATOM feeds as well.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="blog"></category></entry></feed>