<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Boa Blog</title><link href="http://blog.boa.nu/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.boa.nu/feeds/tag-python.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.boa.nu/</id><updated>2012-10-21T20:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Blog technology</title><link href="http://blog.boa.nu/2012/10/blog-technology.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-21T20:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Lars Solberg</name></author><id>tag:blog.boa.nu,2012-10-21:2012/10/blog-technology.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After going back and forth to what technology I wanted behind my blog I decided on;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; as the static blog generator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pelican is written in python, is very extendible with plugins and easy to create themes.
It is also easy to configure and use. The main reason I went with pelican is its simplicity, and possibility to customize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is already other blogs out there that explains &lt;a href="http://blog.aclark.net/yes-this-blog-is-now-powered-by-pelican.html"&gt;pelican advantages and disadvantages&lt;/a&gt; and other blogs that have info about &lt;a href="http://martinbrochhaus.com/2012/02/pelican.html"&gt;using github pages and pelican&lt;/a&gt;, so that is not something I will spend time on here. But if you like to blog using plain-text, python, html/js/css customization and a power full generator to put it into a blog, pelican might be something to check out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="http://fletcherpenney.net/multimarkdown/"&gt;Multimarkdown&lt;/a&gt; as the writing "format"&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multimarkdown is an extension to &lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/"&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt;. Markdown is a structured way of writing articles, snippets, mail or even whole books. It was created as a way to write plaintext which can later be converted to html/pdf/odt/LaTeX or whatever you want, keeping the structure you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, everyone who sends mail on a daily bases should at least look into this. Or at least thing about it. Getting mails that contains a lot of text, and no structure is painful to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to Markdown vs. &lt;a href="http://docutils.sourceforge.net/rst.html"&gt;reStructuredText&lt;/a&gt;, I ended up with markdown because it feels much bigger than rst. Even tough rst is something which the python community uses a lot, it just feels a little dead. I have even tried to use rst for a long time, but it is missing some love from other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="http://pages.github.com/"&gt;Github pages&lt;/a&gt; for hosting the generated html files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love using Github for &lt;a href="https://github.com/xeor/"&gt;my opensourced projects&lt;/a&gt;, so it felt very natural to use their pages to store the html files for my blog. It is free, easy to publish to, and stable. I don't really have much more to say on this. But if my blog was not going to be a bunch of static files, I would probably have used &lt;a href="http://www.heroku.com/"&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="pelican"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="git"></category><category term="github"></category></entry></feed>